{
  "quiz": [
    {
      "question": "How do you create a new BigInteger object?",
      "answer": "By supplying a string with a number like so:<br>BigInteger a = new BigInteger(\"123\");" 
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you create a new BigDecimal object?",
      "answer": "By supplying a string with a number in either int or floating point format:<br>BigDecimal a = new BigDecimal(\"123.5\");<br>or<br>BigDecimal b = new BigDecimal(\"50\");"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you create a new Integer object?",
      "answer": "With either an int or a String like so:<br>Integer a = new Integer(100);<br>or<br>Integer b = new Integer(\"500\");"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you create a new Double object?",
      "answer": "With either a double or a String like so:<br>Double a = new Double(5.15);<br>or<br>Double b = new Double(\"5.0\");"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the MIN_VALUE and the MAX_VALUE for the Integer class?",
      "answer": "These are the max and min values for the primitive data type int.<br>MAX_VALUE = 2,147,483,647<br>MIN_VALUE = -2,147,483,648"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the MIN_VALUE and the MAX_VALUE for the Double class?",
      "answer": "These are the max and min values for the primitive data type double.<br>MAX_VALUE = 1.7976931348623157E308<br>MIN_VALUE = 4.9E-324"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a wrapper class?",
      "answer": "A wrapper class encapsulates the functionality of another class or component. In the case of primitive wrapper classes, such as Double, it allows us to use a primitive as an object and allow greater use of it such as easy conversion to int via the method intValue() found in the Numbers class"
    },
    {
      "question": "What primitive values can a numeric wrapper class convert to?",
      "answer": "The following are NOT static by the way.<br>+doubleValue() : double<br>+floatValue() : float<br>+intValue() : int<br>+longValue() : long<br>+shortValue() : short"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the static method valueOf() of the numeric wrapper classes do? What parameters can it take?",
      "answer": "The static method valueOf() returns an instance of the class it was invoked from such as Integer.valueOf(). It can either take a String or a primitive data type relating to the class it was invoked from.<br>Integer a = Integer.valueOf(\"500\");<br>Integer b = Integer.valueOf(15);"
    },
    {
      "question": "What would foo print if Integer foo = new Integer(\"100\");?",
      "answer": "It would just print 100 and NOT the object's address in memory"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the difference between static methods Integer.parseInt(String s) vs Integer.parseInt(String s, int radix)?",
      "answer": "They both are static methods that return an int. However, the version with the radix returns that string as an int at that base.<br>parseInt(\"473\", 10) == 473<br>parseInt(\"1101\", 2) == 13<br>Long and Short can also use the radix version but not Double or Float<br>Also, for Double the method would be parseDouble(String s) as opposed to parseInt(String s). This remains true for the other primitive wrapper classes."
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you simplify Integer[] arr = {new Integer(2), new Integer(5), new Integer(34)}; and why?",
      "answer": "JDK 1.5 allows primitive type and wrapper classes to be converted automatically so we can now do the following:<br>Integer[] arr = {2, 5, 34};<br>This is known as 'boxing' and retrieving the values out of this array is known as 'unboxing'"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what ways can you construct a String?",
      "answer": "<br>String str1 = \"Hello world!\";<br>String str2 = new String(\"Hola world!\");"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you get the length of an array? A String?",
      "answer": "<br>str.length() : int<br>arr.length : int"
    },
    {
      "question": "What String method is used to find a char at a given index?",
      "answer": "+charAt(int index) : char"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you concatenate two Strings?",
      "answer": "<br>str1 + str2;<br>str1.concat(str2);"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the String method substring() work?",
      "answer": "substring(int beginIndex) returns a new String starting from the given index. 0 would just give the same String all over again.<br>substring(int beginIndex, int endIndex) returns a new String that starts from the beginIndex and stops one before the endIndex<br>\"hellothereguy\".substring(5, 10).equals(\"there\") // resolves to true"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you compare two Strings?",
      "answer": "<br>str1.equals(str2) : boolean"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the String method compareTo() do? What about compareToIgnoreCase()?",
      "answer": "str1.compareTo(str2) compares two strings lexicographically in which we take the unicode value of the first char of the first string and subtracts it from the first char of the second string. This continues until there is a difference and that value is returned as an int. Method compareToIgnoreCase() does the same but ignores case<br>\"apple\".compareTo(\"banana\") == -1<br>If there is no index that they differ then the difference between their String lengths is returned"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you find a char or a substring within a String starting from the beginning?",
      "answer": "<br>indexOf(int c) : int // first occurence<br>indexOf(int c, int fromIndex) : int // begins search from fromIndex, is inclusive<br>indexOf(String str) : int // first occurence<br>indexOf(String str, int fromIndex) : int // begins search from fromIndex"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you find a char or a substring within a String starting from the end?",
      "answer": "<br>lastIndexOf(int c) : int // last occurence<br>lastIndexOf(int c, int fromIndex) : int // searches backwards from fromIndex, is inclusive<br>lastIndexOf(String str) : int // last occurence<br>lastIndexOf(String str, int fromIndex) : int // searches backwards from fromIndex"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you get a String out of a Numeric value?",
      "answer": "Utilize the static toString() methods for the various numeric wrapper classes like so:<br>Integer.toString(myInt) // converts our int into a String<br>Also toString() by itself used with a numeric wrapper object will return it's value as a String"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does it mean for a string to be <i>interned?</i>",
      "answer": "Since strings are immutable and are frequently used, to improve efficiency and save memory, the JVM uses a unique instance for string literals with the same character sequence. Such an instance is called interned.<br>String s1 = \"Hello\";<br>String s2 == new String(\"Hello\");<br>String s3 = \"Hello\";<br>Strings s1 and s3 point to the same interned String while s2 points to a String object for \"Hello\""
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you use the various String replace methods?",
      "answer": "<br>replace(char oldChar, char newChar) : String // replaces all of old with new<br>replaceFirst(String regex, String replacement) : String // replace first substring with that matches regular expression with replacement<br>replace(CharSequence target, CharSequence replacement) : String // replaces all instances of target with replacement<br>replaceAll(String regex, String replacement) : String // similar to replace() with the char sequences but works with regular expressions"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the String method split() work?",
      "answer": "The function split() works by taking a String and splits the String into a String array every time the given String shows up.<br>\"hello#there#world\".split(\"#\") would result in String[] = {\"hello\", \"there\", \"world\"}"
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "answer": ""
    }
  ]
}
